<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Google on Aaron Torres</title>
    <link>http://www.aaron-torres.com/tags/google/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Google on Aaron Torres</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://www.aaron-torres.com/tags/google/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Survey Oops</title>
      <link>http://www.aaron-torres.com/post/google-survey-oops/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.aaron-torres.com/post/google-survey-oops/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, a Google employee made a silly mistake that revealed some unexpected insights.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It started when I received a strange email asking for feedback on one of their coaching program that I had participated in long ago while interviewing. This email was unusual because it skipped my filter, but appeared to be spam at first glance. The title was: “{Action Requested} Google Candidate Coaching Survey”. Even more strangely, the sender used CC for the mailing list revealing 481 email addresses!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Soon after receiving it, people began using reply-all. There was plenty of light-hearted discussion as well including spam complaints and recruiting attempts.  After several replies, a trend appeared &amp;ndash; the majority of individuals had ethnic-sounding names. This observation was brought up in the thread and soon others pointed out you could look at G+ photos from Gmail and that people largely appeared to be ethnic. In total, I received 42 replies and everyone seemed to acknowledge this observation, or at least no one dismissed it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The whole thing was ridiculous and I feel bad for the Google employee who sent it. The lingering questions in my head are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Does Google keep a mailing list of ethnic people?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Were these people targeted for this coaching program?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>